<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-05-09T13:48:23+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Serkan Olgun</title><entry><title type="html">Book Review: Thinking, Fast and Slow</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/05/09/review-book-thinking-fast-and-slow.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Book Review: Thinking, Fast and Slow" /><published>2021-05-09T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-05-09T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/05/09/review-book-thinking-fast-and-slow</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/05/09/review-book-thinking-fast-and-slow.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;float: right; width: 40%; padding: 0px 0px 10px 10px&quot; src=&quot;/img/book-cover-thinking-fast-slow.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his acclaimed book, Thinking, Fast and Slow, psychologist and economist Daniel Kahneman explains how we humans think. He argues we have two systems in action when we think: System 1 and System 2. System 1 is automatic, intuitive, behind-the-scenes and works super fast. System 2, however, is the slow one. This is the rational part of our thinking process though it is also lazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides the concepts of System 1 and 2, several concepts about how humans work, such as Anchoring, Availability, Loss Aversion,Framing, Sunk Costs. These biases and fallacies are all innate within us and they surface when System 1 is in action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like how all the concepts introduced in the book are backed by extensive studies either by the years of collaboration of Kahneman and Tversky, or other renowned scientists in the field of psychology and economics. Each chapter ends with quotes from the real world that exemplifies the concept introduced in the chapter, which helps great to put it in perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daniel Kahneman is expert in behavioral economics and the book mentions a lot about behavioral economics; but this is not an economics or business book per se. It is more about how human brain works especially at times of decisions, which is, of course, also in the domain of behavioral economics on which Kahneman is an expert. So, if you are generally interested in how human brain works at times of decisions, and even remotely interested in behavioral economics, this will be the go-to book for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My rating: 9/10&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12385458-thinking-fast-and-slow&quot;&gt;Goodreads Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Book Review: The Hitchhiker’s Guide to the Galaxy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/04/17/review-book-hitchhikers-guide.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Book Review: The Hitchhiker’s Guide to the Galaxy" /><published>2021-04-17T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-04-17T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/04/17/review-book-hitchhikers-guide</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/04/17/review-book-hitchhikers-guide.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;float: right; width: 40%; padding: 0px 0px 10px 10px&quot; src=&quot;/img/book-cover-hitchhikers.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seconds away from the Earth is being demolished to clear the way for a galactic highway construction, Arthur Dent is saved by his friend Fort Prefect and together they begin their journey through space and their encounters with various space creatures and interesting situations they put themselves in. Sounds very absurd, right? Well… it is exactly that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a classic from Douglas Adams which brings absurd comedy and science fiction together. First of all this is a science fiction novel but also a quite fun read. The comedy in there is utterly absurd —in a good way if you are a fan of absurdity in comedy like myself; otherwise the humor aspect will not appeal to you. That is why people either love HG2G or they don’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are new to The Hitchhiker’s Guide to the Galaxy world, you will be surprised by the number of things you recognize from popular culture, art, engineering etc. which are named after Douglas Adams’ creations in this book. The most striking one for me was Babel, a JavaScript Transpiler which I am familiar with due to my work, which now makes perfect sense why it was named Babe. Once-famous IBM’s chess computer Deep Thought, and it’s answer “42” to the question: “Answer to the Ultimate Question of Life, the Universe, and Everything”. Finally my favorite character Marvin the Paranoid Android, which gives its name to the song by Radiohead in their album OK Computer (1997) which happens to be an album I very much like. More surprisingly later I learned “OK Computer” album name is also coming from The Hitchhiker’s Guide to the Galaxy BBC radio show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is definitely a good choice if you would like to enjoy a science fiction which is also a lot fun. However, if absurdity in comedy is not something for you, you may find this boring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My rating: 9/10&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/42410904-the-hitchhiker-s-guide-to-the-galaxy&quot;&gt;Goodreads Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Kitap İncelemesi: Bunu Herkes Bilir</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/04/01/review-book-bunu-herkes-bilir.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kitap İncelemesi: Bunu Herkes Bilir" /><published>2021-04-01T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-04-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/04/01/review-book-bunu-herkes-bilir</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/04/01/review-book-bunu-herkes-bilir.html">&lt;h4 id=&quot;tarihteki-yanlış-sorulara-doğru-cevaplar&quot;&gt;Tarihteki Yanlış Sorulara Doğru Cevaplar&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;float: right; width: 40%; padding: 0px 0px 10px 10px&quot; src=&quot;/img/book-cover-bunu-herkes-bilir.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bunu herkes bilir, 13 başlıkta tarihteki bazı yanlış soruları ele alıyor ve işin aslını biraz da esprili bir dille açıklıyor. Osmanlı’nin çöküşüne kadınlar mi neden oldu? İstanbul’un fethinde gemiler karadan yürütüldü mu?, Osmanlı Viyana’yı alsaydı Avrupa’ya hükmeder miydi? ve benzeri sorular üzerinden bu soruların neden yanlış olduklarını ve aslında tarihin nasıl okunması gerektiğini anlatıyor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emrah Safa Gürkan’ı Youtube’dan takip ederim. Özellikle genç insanlara tarihin eğlenceli de olabileceğini göstermesini oldukça başarılı buluyorum. Bu kitap da adeta Youtube yayınlarının bir uzantısı gibi. Insanlara tarih kitaplarının da kolay okunabilir ve eğlenceli olabileceğini göstermiş.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yazarın bu kitapta yapmaya çalıştığı şey yazım dilini ve seviyeyi “sıkıcı” kalın tarih kitaplarından biraz aşağı düşürüp, ancak yinede seviyeyi hala biraz yukarıda tutmak ve genel okuyucu kitlesininin entellektüel seviyesini biraz yukarı çıkartmak. Açıkçası yazarın yapmaya çalıştığı şeyi anladım ve iyi bir fikir olduğunu düşündüm. Ancak sonucun tam olarak bu fikri yansıttığını söyleyemem. Çok fazla espri ve laubali dil kullanımı biraz göze batıyor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eğer Emrah Safa Gürkan’i Youtube’dan yakın takip eden biriyseniz, bu kitap size çok tanıdık gelecektir çünkü yazar kitaptaki konuların aşağı yukarı her birini bir Youtube programında anlattı. Yine de bu ilgi çeken konuları kitap formatında Emrah Safa Gürkan’in esprili dilinden okumak zamaniniza değecektir.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Değerlendirmem: 7/10&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/50692738-bunu-herkes-bilir&quot;&gt;Goodreads Sayfası&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Tarihteki Yanlış Sorulara Doğru Cevaplar</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Book Review: Ghost Empire: A Journey to the Legendary Constantinople</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/03/30/review-book-ghost-empire.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Book Review: Ghost Empire: A Journey to the Legendary Constantinople" /><published>2021-03-30T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-03-30T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/03/30/review-book-ghost-empire</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/03/30/review-book-ghost-empire.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;float: right; width: 40%; padding: 0px 0px 10px 10px&quot; src=&quot;/img/book-cover-ghost-empire.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Richard Fidler goes on a journey to Istanbul in 2014 with his teenage son. Whilst he is telling us about their journey in the contemporary Istanbul going on a hunt for the relics of the ancient city, he also begins telling the history, tales and legends of the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story begins even before Constantine I came to Byzantium —from whom the city will eventually take its name. It begins with the path how Constantine the Great becomes a Roman emperor and the events which leads to him settling in the small city of Byzantium. From there, till the fall of Constantinople when Mehmed II (the Conqueror) takes the city and puts an end to the Byzantine Empire, the history of Constantinople is told in a chronological order including many Emperors and Empresses, political &amp;amp; religious struggles, relics such as Hagia Sophia, and many tales and legends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed how Richard Fidler combined the history of Constantinople with his and his son’s journey in the contemporary Istanbul. I was able to relate to their struggle trying to connect to the ancient city as I lived in Istanbul for many years. It was also very interesting to see Istanbul in their perception. For instance, having Atatürk portraits on the walls of the shops is quite common in Turkey to pay respects to the founder of modern Turkey. While it is completely free of any kind of political pressure, I can see how Richard’s son —a teenager who lacks context— can interpret it very differently and compares it with a supreme leader, like Kim Jong-il, for whom you &lt;b&gt;must&lt;/b&gt; pay respects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book should definitely go on your list if you are even remotely interested in the Eastern Roman Empire (a.k.a. Byzantine Empire), legends of one of the capitals of the civilization of that era or early Christianity power struggles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, it is &lt;b&gt;Istanbul not Constantinople&lt;/b&gt; :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My rating: 9/10&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/38471834-ghost-empire&quot;&gt;Goodreads Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Book Review: World History: A New Perspective</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/01/17/review-book-world-history.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Book Review: World History: A New Perspective" /><published>2021-01-17T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-01-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/01/17/review-book-world-history</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/01/17/review-book-world-history.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;float: right; width: 40%; padding: 0px 0px 10px 10px&quot; src=&quot;/img/book-cover-world-history.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“World History” is a colossal topic to tackle in one book; but Clive Ponting did a brilliant job. It is a chronological history of the world. It covers from the first moments of the humans in this world until the end of 20&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; Century.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people consider the human history starts with the Ancient Greeks, continued by the Romans, then together with the rise of Christianity come the European Kingdoms and Dynasties, and with the climactic points of Age of Exploration, Renaissance and Reformation in Europe an economical and cultural domination the Europeans until the rise of United States in the early 20&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; Century and the world as we know it now. This book criticizes such World History view and brings a new perspective. It tries to see the world as a whole, and challenges many assumptions we have regarding the Europeans being the “first” in many things in culture and technology. It argues Asia —China in particular— had progressed economically, culturally and technologically a lot sooner than Europe, and the Europe caught up only later in the 2&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; millennium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was impressing to see how much the history of Mesoamerica, India, China and Japan is covered in detail. I enjoyed in particular the part it explains how much the world of Islam shaped the world by making it possible for different cultures —from the steppes of Asia to the Iberian Peninsula— to be able to interact with each other, which makes it possible from people all around the world learn from each other and progress. This is indeed one of the new perspectives this book introduces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recommend this book for people who would like to get new perspectives on the world history, especially who would like to step away from the Eurocentric view for a while. It is a long read; but I enjoyed it slowly by extending the reading over a long period of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My rating: 8/10&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/555925.World_History&quot;&gt;Goodreads Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Book Review: 20 patterns to watch for in your engineering team</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/01/08/20-patterns-to-watch.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Book Review: 20 patterns to watch for in your engineering team" /><published>2021-01-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-01-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/01/08/20-patterns-to-watch</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/01/08/20-patterns-to-watch.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;float: right; width: 40%; padding: 0px 0px 10px 10px&quot; src=&quot;/img/book-cover-20-patterns.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a collection of 20 work patterns of individuals and teams of Software Engineers, with details of “What is it?” and “How to recognize it?”, as well as suggestions on “What to do?” by Pluralsight. Pluralsight, especially after acquiring GitPrime, has been focused a lot on the data &amp;amp; metrics side of Software Development. Using their experience and expertise, they came up with this guide to help Managers and Leaders with recognizing patterns in their teams and team members, and act accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a short book of 52 pages —half of them are cover pages—, which is easy and concise. Some patterns are quite obvious; but a few of them were very interesting. Although it is not an “eye-opener” material, it is definitely worth the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My rating: 7/10&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/44834750-20-patterns-to-watch-for-in-your-engineering-team&quot;&gt;Goodreads Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pluralsight.com/content/dam/pluralsight2/landing-pages/offers/flow/pdf/Pluralsight_20Patterns_ebook.pdf&quot;&gt;Link to the book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Book Review: Ficciones</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/27/ficciones.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Book Review: Ficciones" /><published>2020-12-27T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-27T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/12/27/ficciones</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/27/ficciones.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;float: right; width: 40%; padding: 0px 0px 10px 10px&quot; src=&quot;/img/book-cover-ficciones.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the collection of 17 short stories —fictions— by Argentine writer Jorge Luis Borges. These stories are sometimes mixture of real and fantasy, and in some cases they are fully fantasy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These stories share a common theme in a very abstract level that is fantasy and philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Tlon, Uqbar, Orbis Tertius”, “The Lottery of Babylon” and “The Library of Babel” are works of a genius. All three stories have the potential to go beyond a short story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though, I wasn’t drawn into all of the stories —especially literary essays—. Mostly this is due to the fact that Borges’ work in these particular stories are esoteric and abstract to an extent that makes them hard to follow without prior knowledge on particular topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considering this is a short book, recommended to anyone to get a glimpse of Borges’ work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My rating: 7/10&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/426504.Ficciones&quot;&gt;Goodreads Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Book Review: Notes from Underground</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/18/notes-from-underground.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Book Review: Notes from Underground" /><published>2020-12-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/12/18/notes-from-underground</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/18/notes-from-underground.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;float: right; width: 40%; padding: 0px 0px 10px 10px&quot; src=&quot;/img/book-cover-notes-from-underground.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a story of a 40-year-old former officer —the narrator— living in his basement in St. Petersburg. “The underground man” tells us how he is alienated from society and ended up living in “underground”. It consists of two parts: first is a monologue from the viewpoint of a 40-year-old spiteful man living in underground, and the second is a haunting memory of him, a very short section of his life that captures his mindset perfectly, back when he was 24.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started noting down his character traits, I realized it had the potential to be an endless list. This is a man who thinks he is an intellectual, cultivated and conscious man unlike everyone around him. He is not modest at all, and thinks he is better than all without doubt. However he has never attained social acceptance, mostly because he is an extremely introvert and insecure man with an inferiority complex. Ultimately he drove himself away from society and became a spiteful man so that even loving meant being morally superior to someone. Despite all, he is honest to himself, sometimes even to the extreme. While I was reading his story, I was angry at him, sympathized with him, happy for him, felt sorry for him, wanted to go to St. Petersburg and confront him…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is clear that Dostoyevsky is a master of human psychology. Several times this book made me stop, think carefully and question myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recommended for anyone who is into psychology. Though keep in mind despite being a short book in number of pages, it is not a short read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My rating: 10/10&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/36190076-notes-from-the-underground&quot;&gt;Goodreads Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Book Review: Deep Work</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/09/review-deep-work.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Book Review: Deep Work" /><published>2020-12-09T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/12/09/review-deep-work</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/09/review-deep-work.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;float: right; width: 40%; padding: 0px 0px 10px 10px&quot; src=&quot;/img/book-cover-deep-work.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deep Work, according the Computer Science Professor Cal Newport, is any activity that is done in a state of distraction free concentration that pushes our cognitive capabilities to their limit, and creates new values that are hard to replicate. Although it sounds straightforward and easy to achieve, it is argued that Deep Work is becoming extremely rare and very valuable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book breaks down the notion of Deep Work and analyzes why it is valuable, rare and meaningful. It also makes it very clear how the Internet is changing our lives on many fronts as well as our capability of performing deep work. The Internet changed our way of life, and it changed how we work. Emails, instant messages, social media are all adding value into our social and work lives; but at a cost usually overlooked: constant distraction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only it defines what Deep Work is and is not at length, but it also provides lots of practical tips to help us cultivate deep work habits. Most of them are very basic ideas; but turning them into habits is the challenge. That is acknowledged clearly in this book, and the tips are catered keeping that in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In one of the chapters, Cal Newport suggests we should quit Social Media. Though this is a provocative statement, the idea was recognized by many; and he based his next book —&lt;a href=&quot;https://serkanolgun.me/2020/06/30/review-book-digital-minimalism.html&quot;&gt;Digital Minimalism&lt;/a&gt;— on that premise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book is mostly for knowledge workers who are struggling with utilizing their time, and anyone who wants to move their work from “Shallow” into “Deep” in order to generate more value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My rating: 7/10&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/27985224-deep-work&quot;&gt;Goodreads Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Book Review: Don’t Overthink It</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/08/review-book-dont-overthink-it.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Book Review: Don’t Overthink It" /><published>2020-11-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-11-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/11/08/review-book-dont-overthink-it</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/08/review-book-dont-overthink-it.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;float: right; width: 40%; padding: 0px 0px 10px 10px&quot; src=&quot;/img/book-cover-dont-overthink-it.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In her book “Don’t Overthink It”, Anne Bogel, a blogger and a podcaster, tries to tackle a major problem a lot of people suffer from: Overthinking. She walks us through the thought patterns which leads to overthinking, and offers practical tips from day-to-day life that can be applied to overcome them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a 217 page, very easy-to-read book. The language used is casual, as if it is a collection of blog posts. On the other hand, the last chapters of the book are in a way that a few distantly related blog posts appended to the book so that it is long enough to be published.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The writer followed a consistent story telling method where she introduces something and backs it by an example story from her life or from the life of one of her family &amp;amp; friends. This method makes sense for certain topics covered in the book; but it is far-fetch for several topics and after a while it becomes repetitive. It could have been shorter and still able to give the same message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the aspects of the notion of Overthinking covered in this book are mainly from the writer’s point of view, and the tips that comes with them are also from her own experience. There are very limited number of ideas presented here that are backed by scientific studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although there are hints especially early in the book that the audience is women, but in fact it’s not exactly. The audience is anyone who is suffering from overthinking, and seeking easy-to-apply tips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My rating: 5/10&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/46161166-don-t-overthink-it&quot;&gt;Goodreads Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>